JOAQUIN STAWSKY

San Diego, CA 92115 • joaquinstawsky@gmail.com • (213) 234-8552 www.github.com/istawsky • www.linkedin.com/in/ioaquin-stawsky

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Data Scientist with 2 years of experience using Python, R, and SQL to produce mathematical models and reach numerical approximations using NOAA climate data, astronomical data, data characterizing grain/seeds, and more. Edited and proofread two mathematics textbooks' code in Python and R, and created a website for one textbook using HTML. Created data-driven solutions to identify the efficiency and deterioration of a grain analysis machine. Conducted machine learning algorithms to classify rice by phenotype better.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

San Diego State University – San Diego, CA – Aug. 2019 - May 2022

Bachelor of Science: Mathematics (Emphasis in Science [Astronomy]), GPA: 3.7

- Honors: Magna Cum Laude, Dean's List (5 out of 6 semesters), Distinction in Mathematics
- Leadership: TAMID Group (Project Manager), Woods.IL (President/Founder)
- Relevant Courses: Ordinary Differential Equations, Programming in Math, Computational Modeling for Scientists, Discrete Math, Real Analysis, Methods of Applied Math, Intercultural Communication, Business Writing and Rhetoric, Linear Algebra, Statistics Principles and Methods

San Bernardino Valley College – San Bernardino, CA (Virtual) – June 2020 - July 2020

• Courses: Modern Physics 210

Moorpark College - Moorpark, CA (Virtual) - July 2020 - Dec. 2020

• Courses: Biological Anthropology M01, Financial Accounting M110

El Camino Real Charter High School – Woodland Hills, CA – Aug. 2015 - June 2019

- Awards: High Honors, Seal of Biliteracy (Spanish), AP Scholar with Distinction (12)
- Leadership: UNICEF Club (President), Recycle 4 Research (Treasurer)

SDG Academy - May 2023

Certification: Climate Action: Solutions for a Changing Planet

EXPERIENCE

Research Fellow - San Diego, CA - Jan. 2022 - Aug. 2022 San Diego State University

- Edited and proofread two Cambridge University Press textbooks in <u>Climate Mathematics</u> and Mathematical Modeling, ensuring accuracy and quality
- Designed the cover photo for the Mathematical Modeling textbook using Python geographical projection techniques, highlighting my creativity and technical skills
- Independently built a website for a textbook, showcasing my self-motivation and ability to learn new technologies
- Oversaw various projects spanning time series analysis, singular value decomposition, energy balance modeling, linear and logistic regression, data mapping, and visualization, demonstrating my diverse skills and expertise

Data Scientist - Tel Aviv, Israel / Remote - June 2021 - Oct. 2021 Vibe Imaging Analytics

- Developed Python-based Overall Equipment Effectiveness software, integrated into primary calibration process to identify suboptimal machines and facilitate improvements in performance.
- Analyzed color and physical attributes of rice, seeds, and wheat grains, improving analysis efficiency by automating data visualization and interpretation for business research, customer-side data visualization, and acquisition activities.
- Successfully implemented three machine learning algorithms achieving +90% accuracy to distinguish between different varieties of grains and seeds

Financial Peer Educator – San Diego, CA – June 2021 – Apr. 2022 San Diego State University

- · Coached and educated SDSU students on financial independence, empowering them to make informed decisions
- Delivered engaging presentations on key financial topics such as budgeting, building credit, banking, loans/financial aid, car buying, and apartment renting
- Collaborated with peers and faculty to design and implement effective financial education programs for the student community

Project Manager Consultant - San Diego, CA - Aug. 2020 - May 2022 TAMID Group at SDSU

- Director of New Member Consulting: Educated 30+ peers on the business basics and tactics
- Investment Funds Manager: Created stock pitches for publicly traded companies
- Project Manager: Organized presentations and worked directly with tech start-ups
- Delegated tasks to and worked alongside my team
- Created and presented 15 deliverables
- Provided data-backed market and industry analysis; website and marketing improvement tactics

- Businesses consulted: Tigon Recruiter - AI Recruitment Agency, and GoTrack - Trucking Logistics Startup Company

Vice President of Finance – San Diego, CA – Aug. 2020 – May 2021 Alpha Epsilon Pi

- Responsible for budget creation and management of Alpha Epsilon Pi (NPO) with a budget of \$50,000+
- Mitigated COVID cuts by decreasing +40% of expenses
- Oversaw all monetary transactions, managed documentation of transactions, and filed taxes

Founder/President – San Diego, CA – Oct. 2020 – May 2021 Woods.IL

- Founded an outdoors club that is free to all through its members' attendance of weekly seminars on current events, sustainability, survival skills, and Israeli education
- Created an inclusive community that provides an escape from our tech-filled lives into the tranquility of nature through camping, hiking, fishing retreats, and more

Administrative Assistant – Los Angeles, CA – June 2019 – Aug. 2020 Merkavah Studio

• Collected and organized payments, blueprints, and scheduled appointments using Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint) at an architectural firm

Personal Tutor – Los Angeles, CA – Aug. 2018 – Aug. 2020 Independent

- · Created, organized, and executed lessons for multiple students in elementary to college-level math classes
- Focused mainly on the development of work ethic and achieved a GPA increase of at least 1.0 in all students

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

• *Skills*: Spanish Biliterate, Beginner Hebrew, Proficient in SQL, HTML, CSS, JS, ADQL, Java, Minitab, and Maple, Fluent in LaTeX, Python, R, and MATLAB, Business Consulting, MS Office: Excel, PowerPoint, Word, Financial Modeling, Fundraising, Scheduling, Program Oversight, Project Management.

SCHOLARSHIPS/FELLOWSHIPS

- NOAA Cooperative Science Center in Atmospheric Sciences and Meteorology Fellowship (Cohort 5) 2022
- Casper Mills Scholarship Award 2019 2022
- JVS Scholarship Award 2019 2022